Victória Morais Santos

Location: Maia, Porto, Portugal

Phone: +351 926 220 332

E-mail: victoria.morais.sa@gmail.com

Portfolio | Linkedin

Profile

A curious Digital accessibility advisor with 8 years of product experience in development, user experience and accessibility. Having worked with companies such as Whirlpool, Embraer - Bradar and currently working at Tangível for AMA as a Digital Accessibility Analyst.

I'm passionate about creating accessible and meaningful solutions that address business needs and improve people's lives.

Education

- Degree in Computer System Analysis at ETEP, 2018.
- Technical in Cartography at UNIVAP, 2008.

Professional experience

2022 to Present: work at Tangível for AMA as a Digital Accessibility Analyst

 Conduct accessibility evaluations and audits using assistive technologies, automated testing tools, and manual testing techniques.

- Collaborate with accessibility experts and teams to promote WEB and mobile applications more accessible in all product development phases.
- Create reports to address accessibility and usability issues with best practices and recommendations in guidelines (WCAG 2.1 and 2.2, AA) and ensuring EN 30 549.
- Share learnings about accessibility, usability and development (basics HTML, CSS and JavaScript).
- · Participation in usability tests with focus on accessibility.

2020 to 2022: work at Whirlpool Corporation as a Product Designer

- Responsible for research activities, surveys creation, interviews and usability tests.
- Collaborate to identify problems and opportunities for improvement in digital products and services.
- Low, Medium and High-fidelity prototypes during ideation of the solution.
- Presentation of the results for the team and business.
- Collaboration in design structure and organization proposing new ideas and possibilities to improve the design process.
- Collaboration, maintenance and improving the style guide brand.

2019 to 2020: work at Corebiz for Whirlpool Corporation as a Product Designer

- Collaboration in research activities, surveys creation, interviews and usability tests.
- Low, Medium and High-fidelity prototypes during ideation of the solution.
- Presentation of the learnings and findings to the team and business.

2019: work at Gama Academy as an UX / UI Designer

- Collaboration in research activities, surveys creation, interviews and usability tests.
- Low, Medium and High-fidelity prototypes during ideation of the solution.
- Collaboration, maintenance and improving the style guide brand.
- Analysis of conversion metrics using tools: Hotjar and Analytics.

2017 to 2018: work at Optimus GIS as a Full stack developer

Part of a team Responsible for building and integrating GIS
web apps that meet the business needs of the client. I helped
develop and execute manual tests.

Skills and learning

- English Intermediate B2 (ICBEU, 2008).
- Develop knowledge and tools: JavaScript, HTML5 / CSS3, Bootstrap, Knockout JS, jQuery, Ajax, SVN, Git; Jira.
- Assistive technologies:
 - Screen readers: NVDA, Voice Over, JAWS, Narrator and Talkback.
 - Switch Access, Voice Control, IOS Voice Control.
- Automatic validations tools: WAVE, Roquet Validator,
 NuValidator, Access Monitor, ANDI, axe DevTools, lighthouse.
- Other tools: Colour Contrast Analyzer, Xcode Accessibility Inspector, Accessibility Viewer, Accessibility Scanner.
- Knowledge of EN 30 549, WCAG 2.1, 2.2, WAI-ARIA.

Design tools: Figma, Adobe (Photoshop, Illustrator, Adobe XD).

Courses and certificates

- IAAP Professional member see IAAP credential
- Preparation course for WAS certification / Deque University (on going).
- · Kick-off training mobile accessibility / Abra Academy, 2024.
- Usability and accessibility gold seal / AMA University, 2023.
- Usability and accessibility bronze and silver seal / AMA University, 2023.
- Web accessibility testing screen readers / Duque University,
 2023.
- Online design courses in UX/UI, Research and Accessibility / Alura, 2023 <u>see all courses completed</u>
- Quantitative methods / Diogo Cortiz, 2022.
- Product discovery / PM3, 2022.
- UX Design course / Belas Artes university, 2019.
- UI Design course / UI Lab, 2019.